Guide to the Carl Feiss papers, [ca.1928]-1991
Feiss, Carl papers, [ca.1928]-1991
- Series II. Professional Papers
  - Projects
    - Greenville County Planning Commission (South Carolina): correspondence, account of Reedy River Study expenses., 1970 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Greenville County Planning Commission (South Carolina): correspondence, "The Economy of Greenville County," "The People of Greenville County.", 1966 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Heritage Hill Historic District: Grand Rapids, Michigan: "Findings of the Historic Inventory," correspondence., 1970-1972 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Heritage Hill Historic District: Grand Rapids, Michigan: "Suggested Procedure for Establishing an Historical Area or District in Grand Rapids," maps, brochure, "Michigan's Marvelous Museums," "The Homes of Heritage Hill," notes, clippings, "Heritage Hill Historic Homes Tour," contract for professional or technical services., 1969 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Heritage Hill Historic District: Grand Rapids, Michigan: "Findings of the Historic Inventory," "Historic/Architectural Survey: Preliminary Report.", 1969-1970 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Heritage Hill Historic District: Grand Rapids, Michigan: map, correspondence., 1970 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Contract between Planning and Engineering Branch, DSCUR, HHFA, USA and Carl Feiss., 1954 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Houston Research Institute: Houston, Texas: "Proposal for a Design Study for a State Planning Program in Texas," "New Mexico State Resources Development Plan," "A Design Study for Capitol Improvements Program in New Mexico.", 1964-1966 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Houston Research Institute: Houston, Texas: correspondence, "A Design Study for a Capital Improvements Program in New Mexico," memoranda, notes, "Economic and Long Range Planning Research, Market Studies and Management Consulting," booklet about HRI., 1965 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments: clipping., 1969 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments: "Final Report to the Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments on a Five Year Policy and Planning Work Program.", 1968 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments: "Final Report to the Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments on Staffing, Administrative Organization and Financing," "Economic Prospects, Problems and Policies: Summary Report.", 1968 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments: "Economic Prospects, Problems and Policies: Preliminary Draft.", 1968 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments: meeting minutes, notes, "Special Instructional and Related Research Program in Community Development," "Final Report to Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments on Urban Decisions Project," "Economic Prospects, Problems and Policies: Preliminary Draft.", 1968 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments: Urban Decisions, questionnaires, meeting agenda., 1967 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments: Governing Urban Society: New Scientific Approaches, notes, clippings, correspondence, "coverage of circular," "Urban Decisions for the Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments," maps, Urban Renewal Agency Annual Report, 1966., 1967 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments: "Common Goals: Uncommon Progress;" Louisville, October 20, 1967; "Goals for Connecticut," Outline of CIPP Phase Summary Report on Open Space and Recreation: The Green Hills of Connecticut.", 1966-1967 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments: Louisville Metropolitan Comprehensive Transportation and Development Program Intermediate Report, Louisville Metropolitan Comprehensive Transportation and Development Program Continuing Phase Work Program., 1966 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Urban Studies Center, University of Louisville: "Louisville and Jefferson County Community Action Commission Evaluation: Final Report," "City of Louisville: Model City Application Abstract," "Report to Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments On Urban Decisions Project.", 1967-1968 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - [empty] (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments: correspondence, meeting minutes, charter, meeting agendas, "Report on Sanitary Sewage: Tentative Broad Outline.", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Falls of the Ohio Metropolitan Council of Governments: correspondence; "Preliminary Evaluation Report on Neighborhood Organizations;" clippings; "Preliminary Summary Statement: Learn More, Earn More;" "Preliminary Summary Evaluation of Intensive Neighborhood Services;" Citizens Metropolitan Planning Council Newsletter; standards and principles for locating police stations, libraries, recreational facilities, hospitals, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Urban Studies Center, University of Louisville: Urban Decisions, notes, "'Met' Council and Education," "When We Sell Our Area, What Are We Selling?", 1967 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Urban Studies Center, University of Louisville: materials re: Neighborhood and Localized Community Self-Organization Project, "Met. Wide Anti-Poverty Planning Urged," clippings., 1967 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: photographs of model of waterfront, 1967 [?] (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: Urban Studies Center, University of Louisville: correspondence., 1966-1967 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Louisville and Jefferson County, Kentucky: "A Search for Sites;" "Organization and Processes for Planning;" Interim Plan 3, 5, 9; clippings., 1966 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Louisville and Jefferson County, Kentucky: "Survey, Analysis and Forecast: The Economic Base and Population.", 1964 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Louisville, Kentucky: materials re: Farmington Museum, clippings, correspondence., 1969 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Macon, Georgia: "Proposal for Preparation of a Preservation and Revitalization Program for the In-Town Historic District, City of Macon, Georgia.", 1978 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments and Mid-Cumberland Development District: Tennessee: "Overall Program Design and Annual Work Program, Fiscal Years 1973-1975:" letter of transmittal, overall program design, financial data, supporting data., 1972 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - [empty] (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments and the Mid-Cumberland Development District:Tennessee: correspondence, narrative progress statement, meeting minutes, Annual Report 5, "Guidelines: Water Quality Management Planning," "Comprehensive Plan for Water and Sanitary Sewer Systems in the Mid-Cumberland Region of Tennessee.", 1971 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Mid-Cumberland Development District and Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments: Tennessee: "Work Program for Human Resource Planning Coordinator submitted to Tennessee Office of Economic Opportunity.", 1971 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - [empty] (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Mid-Cumberland Development District and Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments: Tennessee: meeting minutes, "Overall Program Design and Annual Work Program, Fiscal Year 1973-1975," correspondence, "Report of Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments.", 1971 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - [empty] (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Mid-Cumberland Development District and Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments: Tennessee: "Tennessee Code Annotated," correspondence, Annual Report 3, account of expenses, bylaws of the Mid-Cumberland Development District, "Tennessee State Planning Commission Resolution," Annual Report 4., 1965-1972 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Mid-Cumberland Development District and Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments: Tennessee: untitled publication: "Preface, List of tables, Introduction, Relationship to the Mid-Cumberland Planning Program, Population Characteristics and Projections, Housing Supply, Demand?Ability to Pay, Federally Assisted Housing Programs, Housing Costs and Needs, Housing Program." (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - [empty] (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Mid-Cumberland Development District and Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments: Tennessee: A-95 Project Reviews., 1971 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - [empty] (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Mid-Cumberland Development District and Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments: Tennessee: "A Two-Year Work Program: Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments: Report and Recommendations," "The Status of Planning Operations in the Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments Region: A Report to the Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments," map., 1968 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - [empty] (Box 27, Folder 18-19)
    - Mid-Cumberland Development District and Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments: Tennessee: correspondence, meeting minutes, notes, clippings, "Flight Plan '75.", 1968-1969 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - [empty] (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Mid-Cumberland Development District and Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments: Tennessee: "Planning Program Metropolitan Planning Commission: Nashville and Davidson County," "Tennessee Planning Legislation, 1935-1967," "Tennessee Regions for Comprehensive Planning and Development as Proposed by the State Planning Division," maps, "The Status of Planning Operations in the Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments Region., 1968-1970 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Mid-Cumberland Development District and Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments: Tennessee: correspondence., 1968 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Middle Georgia Historical Society: correspondence, "A Summary Report on The Historic Architecture of Macon, Georgia.", 1970 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Middle Georgia Historical Society: poster advertising a Feiss lecture, clippings, correspondence., 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Middle Georgia Historical Society: correspondence, brochures, memoranda., 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Middle Georgia Historical Society: "Macon Historic Inventory," "The Historic Architecture of Macon, Georgia," maps, brochures, notes, memoranda., 1970 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Middle Georgia Historical Society: clippings, notes., 1969 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Metropolitan Government of Nashville and Davidson County: correspondence., 1971 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): The Matrix, February 1971; April-August 1972., 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): The Matrix, Oct. 1970; correspondence., 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): memoranda., 1970 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - [empty] (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MAATCOG): correspondence, memoranda., 1969 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): untitled publication on MATCOG's health and welfare planning system. (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - [empty] (Box 27, Folder 36-37)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): memoranda, status report, "A Study Design for a Five Year Work Program for the MATCOG," "Work Element 3-A," project memoranda, charts., 1969 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): "Working Paper 3A-1: Physical, Social, and Economic Character of MATCOG Area.", 1969 [?] (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): "Working Paper 3-B: A Five Year Work Program for the MATCOG," "Planning Working Paper Number 1.", 1969 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - [empty] (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): final report outline, correspondence, including "Program Year 1970-1971," "Program Year 1971-1972," "Program Year 1973-1974," "Program Year 1974-1975.", 1969 (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - [empty] (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): correspondence., 1970 (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): correspondence, memorandum., 1970 (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - [empty] (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): correspondence., 1970 (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): correpondence, memoranda, project memoranda., 1970 (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): Executive Committee: meeting minutes., 1970 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): Executive Committee: meeting minutes, Director's Quarterly Report., 1970 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - [empty] (Box 28, Folder 4-5)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): Technical Advisory Committee: project memorandum, notice of meeting, meeting minutes., 1970 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): "Regional Mass Transportation Study?Phase II.", 1970 [?] (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): paper on Crittenden County, Arkansas., 1969 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): paper on Desoto County, Mississippi., 1969 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): materials re: Shelby County, Tennessee., 1970 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - [empty] (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): "Analysis of Existing Condition in the MATCOG Area.", 1969 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): "Five-Year Work Program Planning Activity Recommendations," "The Feasibility of a Regional Information System for the MATCOG," "Five Year Work Program Continuing Program Recommendations.", 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): "Organizational Structure Budgets Five Year Activity Program," transmittal letter., 1970 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Mississippi-Arkansas-Tennessee Council of Governments (MATCOG): "Five Year Program of Operation for the MATCOG: Summary Report.", 1970 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Nashville, Tennessee: brochures, correspondence, clippings., 1970 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Nashville, Tennessee: correspondence., 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Nashville, Tennessee: Tennessee Historical Commission: "A Manual for County by County Survey of Historic Properties in Tennessee," correspondence., 1969 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - [empty] (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - National Capitol Planning Commission: clippings, correspondence, preliminary draft of Report on the Program for a Study of the Skyline of the Nation's Capital," interview with Harlean James, Yates Cook, Mort Hoppenfeld, Working Paper 2: Skyline Study, press release, "contract for study and report concerning the design functions of open-space land in urban areas.", 1963-1964 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - National Capitol Planning Commission: Open Space Project: "Open Space Study," including correspondence and notes., 1963 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - National Capitol Planning Commission: Open Space Project: "General Work Program;" Metropolitan Communique, September/October 1963; notes, drafts of "Open Space Study," correspondence. (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - National Capitol Planning Commission: Landscape Preservation Project: "Program for Landmarks Conservation in the District of Columbia.", 1962-1963 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - National Capitol Planning Commission: Historic Landmarks, Washington, D.C.: list of members, clippings, correspondence, memoranda., 1962-1963 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - National Capitol Planning Commission: Historic Landmarks, Washington, D.C.: correspondence., 1962 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - National Capitol Planning Commission: Historic Landmarks, Washington, D.C.: correspondence re: payment for Feiss' consultation., 1962-1963 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - National Commission for Urban Problems: "Standards for Urban Development in the United States: Development Standards, Systems and Regulations Used for their Implementation in Urbanizing America.", 1968 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - National Commission for Urban Problems: award/contracts, correspondence, "Recommendations," press releases, "Development Standards and the Urban Development Process," "Summary Statement on Study of Moderate and Low Income Housing Programs," progress report, clippings., 1968 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - [empty] (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - National Endowment for the Arts/National Council on the Arts: correspondence re: Feiss' "invitation to serve as consultant.", 1971 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - National Endowment for the Arts/National Council on the Arts: correspondence, press releases., 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - National Endowment for the Arts/National Council on the Arts: "An American Guide Series: A Prospectus.", 1969 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - National Endowment for the Arts/National Council on the Arts: correspondence re: tour guide expenses., 1968 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - National Endowment for the Arts/National Council on the Arts: correspondence, list of programs., 1969 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - National Endowment for the Arts/National Council on the Arts: correspondence., 1966-1967 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - National Endowment for the Arts/National Council on the Arts: clippings, proposal for "A National Guide Series of American Architecture and the Allied Arts.", 1966 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - National Resources Planning Board: Urban Section: "Memorandum on Urban Financing: Analysis of Municipal Finance with Reference to Urban Planning no. 1: Fiscal Problems of Urban Areas, Alternative Measures in Local Finance.", 1942 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - National Resources Planning Board: correspondence, appointments, assignments, travel authority, monthly activities reports, transportation requests, travel authorities, travel vouchers, salary reports, salary statements, special expenses, diary., 1942 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - National Resources Planning Board: correspondence, appointments, assignments, travel authority, monthly activities reports, transportation requests, travel authorities, travel vouchers, salary reports, salary statements, special expenses, diary., 1941 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - National Resources Planning Board: Dead File: Defense Activities: Hampton Roads, Richmond, Virginia: general data, maps, reports, correspondence; Area of Wilmington, North Carolina: correspondence, reports, general data, maps., 1941 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - National Science Foundation: correspondence, "Interim Description and Guidelines for Proposal Preparation.", 1972 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Nationwide Insurance: annual report, correspondence, memoranda, "Proposed Development Plan for North Core Area.", 1963-1965 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - [empty] (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Nationwide Insurance: correspondence., 1963-1964 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Nationwide Insurance: Columbus, Ohio: "Downtown Development Study: Columbus, Ohio," "Prospectus for Preparation of a Comprehensive Regional Plan: Columbus-Franklin County," "Long-Range Growth Potential of the Columbus and Southern Ohio Electric Company Study Area.", 1964 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Nationwide Insurance: "Remarks of Daniel M. Ogden, Jr. [?] before the 19th Convention of the National Association of Soil and Water Conservation Districts, Portland, Oregon, February 9, 1965," correspondence, memoranda, "discussion outline of re-use potential central core north.", 1964-1965 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Oak Ridge National Laboratory: "Annual Progress Report: Civil Defense Research Projects, March 1968-March 1969," "Conceptual Design of a Dual-Use Utility Tunnel Blast Shelter for White Plains, New York.", 1968-1969 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - [empty] (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Palm Beach County Area Planning Board: "Palm Beach County As Seen By the Residents.", 1969 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Palm Beach County Area Planning Board: Sans Souci Hotel brochure; apb Forum, February 1969; meeting minutes, meeting agendas, "Palm Beach Community Characteristics Analysis: Progress and Findings to Date?October 29, 1968;" "Economy and Population: Palm Beach Economic Region?Overview.", 1968-1969 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Palm Beach County Area Planning Board: correspondence, questionnaires, meeting minutes, meeting agenda, "Contract for Personal Services: Urban Planning Assistance Project Area Planning Board Palm Beach County.", 1968-1969 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Palm Beach County: "Interviews with Community Leaders in Palm Beach County.", 1968 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - [empty] (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Palm Beach County Area Planning Board: meeting minutes, meeting agendas, correspondence, clippings., 1967 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Pensacola, Florida: Historic Pensacola Preservation Board: "The Restoration of Historic Pensacola," correspondence, memorandum, "Agreement Between the Pensacola Historical Restoration and Preservation Commission and City Planning and Architectural Associates.", 1970 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Pensacola, Florida: Historic Pensacola Preservation Board: correspondence., 1970 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Pensacola, Florida: Historic Pensacola Preservation Board: correspondence., 1969 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Pensacola, Florida: Historic Pensacola Preservation Board: map of historic structures., 1969 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Pensacola, Florida: Historic Pensacola Preservation Board: correspondence., 1969 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Pensacola, Florida: Historic Pensacola Preservation Board: purchase order, correspondence, photograph, "Heirloom Recipes," brochure for "Seville Square," map of proposed zoning?historical boundary, clippings, maps, "Proposed Pensacola Urban Area Transportation Study," memorandum., 1968 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Pensacola, Florida: Historic Pensacola Preservation Board: maps, correspondence, notes, "Proposed Zoning?Historic District," House Bill creating the Pensacola Historical Restoration and Preservation Commission," Pensacola Historical Restoration and Preservation Commission Master Plan.", 1968 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Pensacola, Florida: "Historic Development Plan for the City of Pensacola, Florida.", 1967 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - [empty] (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Pike Plaza Redevelopment Project: Seattle, Washington: clippings, correspondence, business cards., 1971 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Pike Plaza Redevelopment Project; Seattle, Washington: clippings, "Pike Plaza," layouts of Plaza, "Excepts from Final Report," photographs of Pike Plaza model, illustration of site plan., 1971 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Puerto Rico, University: correspondence, "Application for Urban Renewal Demonstration Grant: Impact of Government Programs on Historic Preservation in Old San Juan.", 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Puerto Rico, University: "Summary Report to the Commission on Revisions to Zoning Regulation no. 4," "The Role of the Colegio in Planning and Development Policy for the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico," correspondence, clippings, "A Petition to the Planning Board of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico," "Informe del Comite de Evaluacion," notes, "Summary Report: San Juan Metropolitan Area Transportation Study: Transportation Plan.", 1968 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - [empty] (Box 30, Folder 10)